Guide to the Henry White Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Henry White papers
1745-1886
MS 551
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.5
(16 boxes)
Chiefly correspondence and legal papers of the law firm founded in New Haven by Henry White's father, Dyer White, in 1785. Henry White joined the firm in 1828. Records of 113 individuals, firms, and estates whose business the firm handled make up the business section of the papers. Also included are a small amount of Dyer White's family correspondence (1784-1836) and college lecture notes, account books related to church activities (1822-1837), and other miscellaneous papers of Henry White.
White, Henry, 1803-1880
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Roger S. White, the White law office, and Mr. Sanborn, 1913-1925.
Scope and Contents
The Henry White Papers, 1745-1886, consist of 6.5 linear feet of business, legal, and personal papers from the offices of Henry White, lawyer of New Haven. This firm, founded in 1785 by his father, Judge Dyer White (1762-1841), became White Brothers in 1880, when Henry White died, leaving the business to his sons. The papers are mainly those of individuals, firms, and estates whose business the firm handled. Also included are some papers of Dyer White as New Haven officeholder, some personal letters, and several lectures delivered by Henry White at Yale College and before the Mechanics' Society and the Young Men's Institute.
The Henry White Papers came to the Library from Roger S. White, from the White law offices, and from a Mr. Sanborn between 1913 and 1925.
Biographical / Historical
HENRY WHITE, the only surviving child of the Hon. Dyer and Hannah (Wetmore) White, was born in New Haven, Conn., March 5, 1803.
He received his BA from Yale in 1821. From 1823 to 1825 he served as a tutor at Yale. He then studied law, and entered on its practice in 1828 in his native city, where he continued to reside until his sudden death, from neuralgia of the heart, Oct. 7, 1880, at the age of 77. His tastes led him to appear rarely in court, but he was specially occupied with the settlement of estates and the care of trust funds, and in these duties had the entire confidence of the community through a long life. He was also much interested in matters of local history and had given particular attention to the compilation of a history of the ownership of land in New Haven. He was one of the founders and the first president of the New Haven Colony Historical Society. For nearly half a century he was a deacon in the Center Church. He was married, Jan. 7, 1830, to Martha, daughter of Roger Sherman, of New Haven, and granddaughter of the Hon. Roger Sherman. She survived him with six sons, graduates of this College in 1851, 1854, 1859, 1860, 1864 and 1866, a seventh son having died a few months before his father.
Obituary Record of Graduates of Yale University, 1880-1890.
Families; Law; New Haven (Conn.) -- History; New Haven (Conn.) -- Religion; Account books; Lawyers; White, Dyer, 1762-1841; White, Henry, 1803-1880; White, Sally; White family; Yale University -- Students
- Inventory, 1745-1886; 6.5 linear feet (16 boxes)
  - Correspondence and other papers relating to legal practice, 1799-1880
    - Atwater - Bostwick (Box 1)
      - Atwater, Jeremiah, 1853-1871 (Box 1)
      - Atwood, Charles, 1839-1840 (Box 1)
      - Augur, Hezekiah, 1834-1856 (Box 1)
      - Augustus, Scipio, 1817-1854 (Box 1)
      - Bacon, Asa, 1847-1874 (Box 1)
      - Bacon, Frederick A., 1860-1869 (Box 1)
      - Baldwin, Martha N., 1861-1874 (Box 1)
      - Barber, George C., 1832- (Box 1)
      - Barker, Charles S., 1863-1865 (Box 1)
      - Bassett, John G., 1833-1867 (Box 1)
      - Beers, Timothy P., 1858-1864 (Box 1)
      - Benson, Wm. E. & Jennie, 1868-1873 (Box 1)
      - Bostwick, Wm., 1839-1868 (Box 1)
    - Bostwick (cont'd) - Collins (Box 2)
      - Bostwick, Wm., 1839-1868 (Box 2)
      - Bradley, Abraham, 1835-1845 (Box 2)
      - Bradley, John, 1827-1868 (Box 2)
      - Brown, Mercy, 1802-1846 (Box 2)
      - Bulkly, Henry D., 1863 (Box 2)
      - Burrows, Silas E. & John R., 1860-1873 (Box 2)
      - Butler, Sarah V. H., 1854-1880 (Box 2)
      - Collins, David C. & Clarissa E., 1841-1879 (Box 2)
    - Cooke - Dexter (Box 3)
      - Cooke, John, 1825-1879 (Box 3)
      - Daggett Family, 1787-1876 (Box 3)
      - Daggett, Oliver E., 1850-1867 (Box 3)
      - Darling Family, 1796-1872 (Box 3)
      - Dexter, Normand, 1826-1837 (Box 3)
    - Dickerman - Hallock (Box 4)
      - Dickerman, James P., 1855-1879 (Box 4)
      - Dutcher, L. L., 1848-1859 (Box 4)
      - Dwight, Timothy, 1826-1829 (Box 4)
      - Eagle Bank, 1826-1835 (Box 4)
      - Elliot, Wm. H., 1861-1870 (Box 4)
      - Elliot, Wm. H., Jr., 1853 (Box 4)
      - Ellsworth, Henry L., 1859-1870 (Box 4)
      - Forbes, Wm. J., 1839-1866 (Box 4)
      - Goodrich, James W., 1850-1871 (Box 4)
      - Goodyear, Nelson, 1851 (Box 4)
      - Greene, David, 1822-1843 (Box 4)
      - Greene, Mary A., 1864-1875 (Box 4)
      - Griswold, Leverett (Box 4)
      - Hallock, Gerard, 1837-1864 (Box 4)
      - Hallock, Jeremiah H., 1848-1852 (Box 4)
      - Hallock, Wm. A., 1835-1844 (Box 4)
    - Herrick - Hughes (Box 5)
      - Herrick, Eunice T., 1866-1868 (Box 5)
      - Hillhouse, Mary L., 1845-1878 (Box 5)
      - Hitchcock, Samuel J., 1835-1863 (Box 5)
      - Holcombe, Hiram, 1829-1844 (Box 5)
      - Hoppin, J. M. (Box 5)
      - Horton, Mary D., 1859-1878 (Box 5)
      - Hotchkiss, Samuel R., 1836-1881 (Box 5)
      - Howe, Hezekiah, 1799-1851 (Box 5)
      - Howe Street Church, 1858 (Box 5)
      - Hoyt, W. W., 1852-1859 (Box 5)
      - Hubbard, James M., 1861-1878 (Box 5)
      - Hubbell, H. W. & Jane M., 1848-1862 (Box 5)
      - Hughes, Samuel, Estate, 1845-1875 (Box 5)
    - Hughes (cont'd) - Leffingwell (Box 6)
      - Hughes, Samuel, Estate, 1845-1875 (Box 6)
      - Ives, Eli, 1839-1864 (Box 6)
      - Jenkins, Joseph and Wealthy Ann, 1839-1862 (Box 6)
      - Jewett, Stephen, 1865-1879 (Box 6)
      - Jones, Betsey, 1849-1873 (Box 6)
      - Kansas Relief Com., 1861 (Box 6)
      - Ketcham, Lucy D., 1858-1879 (Box 6)
      - Leffingwell Family, 1797-1875 (Box 6)
    - Lockwood - Percival (Box 7)
      - Lockwood, Le Grand, 1857-1870 (Box 7)
      - Merriman, Betsey, 1822-1860 (Box 7)
      - Mix, Silas, 1849-1853 (Box 7)
      - Mix, William, 1866-1869 (Box 7)
      - New Englander, 1847-1852 (Box 7)
      - New Haven Almshouse, 1852-1874 (Box 7)
      - New Haven Book Club, 1848-1874 (Box 7)
      - Norton, Dudley, 1858-1860 (Box 7)
      - Ogden, Mary C., 1802-1844 (Box 7)
      - Olmstead, Henry, 1863 (Box 7)
      - Paddock, Dr., 1855-1856 (Box 7)
      - Parsons, Samuel, 1857-1869 (Box 7)
      - Peck, Mary, 1859-1865 (Box 7)
      - Peck & Stafford, 1846-1851 (Box 7)
      - Percival, James G., 1835-1857 (Box 7)
    - Phelps - Sherman (Box 8)
      - Phelps, Anson G., 1846-1864 (Box 8)
      - Pomeroy, Elizabeth, 1832-1859 (Box 8)
      - Ray, Anna, 1830-1833 (Box 8)
      - Rianhart, William E., 1848-1867 (Box 8)
      - Root, Joel, 1821-1853 (Box 8)
      - Sage, Oliver, 1832-1836 (Box 8)
      - Salisbury, Edward E., 1847-1874 (Box 8)
      - Seeley, Ebenezer, 1837-1842 (Box 8)
      - Sheffield, Joseph B., 1849-1855 (Box 8)
      - Sheffield, William, 1842-1847 (Box 8)
      - Sherman, Thaddeus, 1858-1878 (Box 8)
    - Skinner - Wales (Box 9)
      - Skinner, John, 1803-1880 (Box 9)
      - Spencer Estates, 1839-1857 (Box 9)
      - Spencer, Horatio N. & I. S., 1853-1857 (Box 9)
      - Stone, Sidney M., 1843-1853 (Box 9)
      - Street, Augustus R., 1867-1875 (Box 9)
      - Tomlinson, Charles, 1852-1873 (Box 9)
      - Townsend, Anna, 1848-1859 (Box 9)
      - Tyler, Edward R., 1848-1850 (Box 9)
      - Upson, Henry, 1853-1879 (Box 9)
      - Wadsworth, Mary, 1859-1862 (Box 9)
      - Wales, John H., 1818-1821 (Box 9)
    - Webster - Wetmore family (Box 10)
      - Webster, Louisa, 1873-1876 (Box 10)
      - Webster, Noah, 1843-1876 (Box 10)
      - Western College Soc., 1852-1878 (Box 10)
      - Wetmore Family, 1823-1877 (Box 10)
    - White - Yale, Misc. (1745-1846) (Box 11)
      - White, Eunice, 1830-1869 (Box 11)
      - Whitney, Eli, 1863-1865 (Box 11)
      - Wickham, Joseph D., 1859-1878 (Box 11)
      - Wight, O. W., 1854-1862 (Box 11)
      - Williams, Cyrus, 1844-1869 (Box 11)
      - Winship, James, 1868-1875 (Box 11)
      - Wise, Sally, 1849-1861 (Box 11)
      - Woolsey, T. D., 1873 (Box 11)
      - Wooster, Joseph L., 1775-1796 (Box 11)
      - Yale, 1821-1864 (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1745-1846 (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1847-1880, undated (Box 12)
  - Family correspondence
    - Incoming and outgoing letters of Dyer White, 1784-1813 (Box 12)
    - Sally White to Dyer White, 1793-1836 (Box 12)
  - White family genealogy, undated (Box 12)
  - Notebooks
    - "Explanation of the Bible...,", 1810 (Box 13)
    - Mathematics exercise book, 1810 (Box 13)
    - "Extracts of Sermons from various Authors,", 1815 (Box 13)
    - Account book of the Female Auxiliary Bible Society of New Haven and Vicinity, 1822-1825 (Box 13)
    - Account book of church subscriptions, 1837 (Box 13)
    - Names and locations of soldiers buried in Grove Street cemetery, 1886 (Box 13)
  - Lecture notes
    - Natural history lectures for the Young Men's Institute, 1831-1833 (Box 13)
    - College lectures on various subjects, undated (Box 13)
  - Classified extracts from early New Haven records, with notes, undated (Box 14)
  - Collection of slips possibly used to prepare New Haven land records, [1844?] (Box 15)
  - Collection of slips possibly used to prepare New Haven land records, [1844?] (Box 16)